Hit enter to search or ESC to close

[

](https://advangelists.com/)

Who we are
----------

Our website address is: https://advangelists.com.

What personal data we collect and why we collect it
---------------------------------------------------

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website

### Contact forms

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, CCPA and GDPR).

We may collect information about you for 2 reasons: firstly, to process your order and second, to response to any queries which you may have.

We will not e-mail you in the future unless you have given us your consent.

We will give you the chance to refuse any marketing email from us in the future.

The type of information we may collect about you includes:

* your name
* email address
* IP Address
* Any additional information you willingly provide by submitting a contact form

We will never collect information about you without your explicit consent.

The information we hold will be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by emailing us. If you find any inaccuracies we will delete or correct it promptly.

The personal information which we hold will be held securely in accordance with our internal security policy and the law.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Analytics

#### Who we share your data with

#### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

#### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

####  Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Cookies
-------

This Cookie Policy explains how Advangelists and its affiliates (collectively “Advangelists”, “we“, “us“, and “ours“) use cookies and similar technologies to recognise you when you visit our websites or websites of advertising partners (“Website“).  It explains what these technologies are and why we use them, as well as your rights to control our use of them.

### **What are cookies?**

Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are widely used by publishers in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, Advangelists) are called “first party cookies.”  Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called “third party cookies.” Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the Website (e.g. like interactive content and analytics). The parties that set these third party cookies can recognize your computer both when it visits the Website and also when it visits certain other websites.

### **What cookies do we use?**

We use first party and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Websites to operate. Other cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Websites. We may also use cookies for analytics or other purposes.

The specific types of first and third party cookies served through our Websites and the purposes they perform are described in the table below:

### **Types of third party cookies**

Essential website cookies: These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our Websites and to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas.

Who serves these cookies: Advangelists

How to refuse: because these cookies are strictly necessary to deliver the Websites to you, you cannot refuse them. You can block or delete them by changing your browser settings however, as described below under the heading “How can I control my cookies?”

Performance and functionality cookies: These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our Websites but are non-essential to their use.  However, without these cookies, certain functionality may become unavailable.

Analytics and customisation cookies: These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how our Websites are being used or how effective are marketing campaigns are, or to help us customise our Websites for you.

Who serves these cookies: Google Analytics

To refuse these cookies, please follow the instructions below under the heading “How can I control My cookies?”

**Web beacons and other technologies**

Cookies are not the only way to recognize or track visitors to a website.  We may use other, similar technologies from time to time, like web beacons (sometimes called “tracking pixels” or “clear gifs”).  These are tiny graphics files that contain a unique identifier that enable us to recognise when someone has visited our Websites or opened an e-mail that we have sent them.  This allows us, for example, to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our Websites to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our Websites from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website, to improve site performance, and to measure the success of e-mail marketing campaigns.  In many instances, these technologies are reliant on cookies to function properly, and so declining cookies will impair their functioning.

**How can I control my cookies?**

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies.  You can exercise your cookie preferences by following the opt-out instructions below.

Your Opt-Out Choices

Because the effect of “Do Not Track” signals remains unclear, and there continues to be no consistent industry understanding of how to respond to such a signal, we do not alter our privacy practices when we detect a “Do Not Track” signal from your browser. Nonetheless, there are many ways to opt-out of the use of Advangelists technology for purposes of delivering targeted advertisements. Please see our advertising technology privacy policy should you wish to do so.

You can also refuse or accept cookies from the Website at any time by activating settings on your browser.  Information about the procedure to follow in order to enable or disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website via your help screen.  You may wish to refer to http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html for information on commonly used browsers. Please be aware that if cookies are disabled, some website features may not operate as intended.

Please note that opt-outs operate by placing a cookie on your device that is unique to the browser and device you use to opt-out. They may not function properly if you have configured your browser to reject certain cookies. If you change browsers or computers, or delete the cookies on your computer, you will need to opt-out again. You also can set your browser to notify you when a cookie is being set and to block most cookies, including ours.

**How often will you update this Cookie Statement?**

We may update this Cookie Statement from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to the cookies we use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.  Please therefore re-visit this Cookie Statement regularly to stay informed about our use of cookies and related technologies.

The date at the top of this Cookie Statement indicates when it was last updated.

### **Where can I get further information?**

If you have any questions about our use of cookies or other technologies, please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://advangelists.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Data Opt Out Policy
-------------------

Advangelists respects the data protection and privacy rights you may have under applicable privacy laws (often referred to as “data subject rights“ or “consumer privacy rights”).

As explained in our privacy policy, our advertising technology does not collect information that directly identifies you as an individual (such as your name or email address). Instead, it only collects certain digital identifiers that enable us to recognize your device or your Internet browser (each, a “Digital Identifier”).

For that reason, in order for us to honor any data protection and privacy requests you submit, we need you to provide us with your Digital Identifiers and certain other information.  This is necessary to locate any records we hold about your device or browser. We explain below how to do this, and use this additional information only for the purpose of processing your data protection and privacy requests.

YOUR RIGHTS EXPLAINED
---------------------

Residents of some jurisdictions , including California, have certain rights available to them under the laws of those jurisdictions.

These rights may include the right to request access to, rectify, or request erasure/deletion or portability of, personal information. Residents of these jurisdictions may also have a right to object to, or request that we restrict, processing of their personal information. Where such rights apply, we will comply with requests to exercise these rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. We will also make efforts to honor such requests even in jurisdictions that do not provide for these rights

If you make a request to access the specific pieces of personal information we hold about you in accordance with applicable law (also known as an “access request“), we will provide the Digital Identifiers of your browser(s) and/or device(s) that Advangelists may store. Additionally, we may also provide you with certain other information that we may have stored and associated with your Digital Identifiers.

Please note, however, that we have a very short retention period for the data we associate with Digital Identifiers. As a result, we may not be able to provide you any records in response to an access request. In such cases, however, we will inform you that we have not been able to locate any records associated with your Digital Identifiers.

Important Note: We have a responsibility to verify your identity before we respond to an access request. This is to make sure that we provide a copy of your personal information only to the person who is entitled to it – you. If you wish to make an access request, we kindly ask that you contact us directly, with sufficient details for us to verify your identity (as explained below).

**HOW TO MAKE A DATA RIGHTS REQUEST**
-------------------------------------

If you wish to exercise a data subject rights request, please follow the steps described below:

### Step 1: Locate Your Digital Identifiers

In order for us to locate relevant records, we will need you to provide us with your Digital Identifiers. You can find your Digital Identifiers as follows:

#### _Web Browsing_

As described in our privacy policy, our advertising technology operates by using text files called “cookies” that are placed on your device. Some of these cookies include a Digital Identifier. To locate these Digital Identifiers, you can search through your cookies for the cookies named “khaos” and “ruid” (which are set from the advangelists.com domain). The text in each of these cookies is a separate Digital Identifier.

Please keep in mind that different cookies are placed on each browser that you use to access the Internet. As a result, if you use multiple browsers (for example, Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox), you will need to locate the “khaos” and “ruid” cookies for each browser.

#### _Mobile Devices and other Internet Connected Devices_

Additionally, certain mobile devices (for example, mobile phones or tablets using the iOS or Android operating systems) generate a persistent “Advertising Identifier” per device, which, among other things, can be used by third parties, like Advangelists, for purposes of providing you with targeted advertising.

On iOS devices, your Advertising Identifier may be referred to as an “IDFA,” “IFA,” or an “ID for Advertising.” On Android devices, your Advertising Identifier may be referred to as an “Advertising ID.” Please follow instructions from your mobile device manufacturer on how to locate your specific Advertising Identifier.

### Step 2: Verify Your Digital Identifiers

In order to make sure that we are responding to the correct person, we also will need some supporting proof to demonstrate that the devices that have the Digital Identifiers you located in Step 1 are yours and that the information you are requesting relates to you.  For Digital Identifiers stored in cookies, please take a screenshot of each cookie, taking care to make sure that the screenshot shows both the name of the cookie and the full Digital Identifier. For Digital Identifiers located on a mobile device, please take a screenshot of a screen that displays the Digital Identifier.

We may also request that you respond to a few questions, so that we can appropriately verify your identity. Doing this helps us to validate that you have access to the device on which the Digital Identifiers have been placed (and that you are not an unauthorized third party attempting to “guess” Digital Identifiers).

### Step 3: Submit to Advangelists

Once you have located your Digital Identifiers and can provide us with verification of those Digital Identifiers, please email [\[email protected\]](https://advangelists.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with details of the rights you wish to exercise.. We will request the following information:

* Your full name
* The region in which you are located at the time you are making your request
* The data subject rights you wish to exercise
* A full list of your Digital Identifiers
* Device validation information, as set forth in Step 2
* Identity certification

Technology Privacy Policy
-------------------------

This policy applies to the information Advangelists (“Advangelists,” “we” or “us”) collects and receives from individuals (“end users” or “you”) who interact with Digital Media Properties (defined below) that use Advangelists’s technology to provide you with ads. Advangelists is committed to transparency, and we want you to fully understand how we may collect, use, and share information relating to individuals (like you), and the choices that are available to you.

_**Please note:**_

This privacy policy does not govern (i) the collection and use of information about visitors to our website (https://advangelists.com) – that information can be found here; or (ii) our clients’ collection, use and disclosure of information through their Digital Media Properties (defined below), which is governed by their own privacy policies and practices.  For these purposes, our clients include advertisers and publishers as described below under the heading “About Us.”

### **About Us**

Advangelists provides a digital advertising technology platform and related services that connects advertising buyers (advertisers) with sellers (publishers) of advertising inventory (in other words, the opportunity to display a buyer’s advertisement on a seller’s Digital Media Property).  In this policy, we refer to our buyers and sellers collectively as “clients”.

For example, advertisers (or their agents) use our technology to buy advertising for display on publishers’ websites, mobile applications, television, and other digital media properties (which we collectively refer to as “Digital Media Properties”). We also provide related software and APIs for developers. 

### **Information We Collect**

When you visit a Digital Media Property that uses our technology, we collect certain information about you and your device (collectively, “User Information”). This information does not directly identify you – we don’t collect your name or contact details – but it may be considered “personal data” or “personal information” under applicable privacy or data protection laws.

In particular, we collect identifiers such as your IP addresses, cookie identifiers, and mobile device identifiers. These identifiers may identify a particular computer, mobile device, television, or other device. We also collect information about your activity online, including the following categories of internet or electronic network activity:

* Information about your behavior on our publishers’ Digital Media Properties: including information about the domain, topic or name of property, your referring website addresses, date/time of visits, view data, search keywords, visitor activities and actions on publisher’s properties, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, non-precise location information (including city, country, zip code), click data, types of advertisements viewed;
* Information about your browser: including information about your browser type, version, language, and history;
* Information about your device: including information about your IP address, device make, device model, device operating system, device operating system version, and data connection type; and
* Information about your Internet service: including information about which Internet Service Provider (ISP) you use.

We may also collect precise geolocation information if you have actively enabled location services on your device and a Digital Media Property passes it to us.

Our clients may collect and store inferences about user activity using our technology. The Advangelists does not itself make inferences about users interests or preferences, but others may do so using our platform.

### **How We Collect User Information**

We use cookies and other standard web technologies to collect information automatically from your device when you engage with a Digital Media Property that uses our technology.  Please review our Platform Cookie Statement for further information.

Other technologies: Additionally, we use other technologies, including local storage, to collect User Information in order to assist with the delivery of ads and to provide reporting to our customers.

We also work with third-party advertising platforms that separately collect and use User Information to enable our and their customers to deliver targeted advertisements using our advertising technology. As an example, we work with third-party advertising companies that use information about your visits to various websites or applications across multiple devices in order to provide you content and ads of interest across devices that they think are associated with you or your household, including web browsers, mobile apps, and televisions. Our clients may use this third-party data in combination with the User Information we collect to deliver you targeted ads across multiple devices.

**How We Use User Information**

Our clients use User Information in order to buy and sell advertising space on Digital Media Properties. In particular, our clients use information we provide, in conjunction with other information they have independently collected, to deliver end users targeted advertising they believe will be of particular interest to those users. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

We also use the User Information we collect for our legitimate business interests, some of which are “business purposes” under California law, including:

* To enable our clients to offer and buy advertising opportunities on Digital Media Properties;
* To operate and improve our technology;
* To compile statistics and conduct research and development for our internal business purposes – all of which is done in aggregate without identifying you;
* To prepare reports that summarize visitor activity;
* To enable standard advertising controls;
* To analyze and report on ad performance (such as tracking views of ad, as well as click-through rates on ads), campaign reporting, and campaign forecasting; and
* To protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.
* Sharing of User Information

#### **We disclose User Information that we collect as follows:**

* Clients: We share User Information with our advertiser clients to help them identify and buy advertising on publishers’ Digital Media Properties. Clients may use this information in conjunction with other information they have independently collected to provide you targeted advertising and to help them evaluate whether a particular ad campaign may be of interest to you.
* Business Transfers: We may share User Information in connection with an actual or proposed sale or transfer of all or a part of our business or assets, corporate merger, consolidation, or bankruptcy.
* Vital interest, legal rights and compliance with laws. We may share User Information with law enforcement, regulatory authorities, courts with competent jurisdictions, emergency services or other necessary third parties for legal, protection, security, and safety purposes, including:
    * to comply with laws or regulatory requirements and to respond to lawful requests and legal process;
    * to protect the rights and property of Advangelists, our agents, customers, and others, including enforcing our agreements, policies, and terms of use and protecting our network and physical assets; and/or
    * to protect the safety of our employees and agents, our customers, or any person.
* Vendors, partners and other service providers: We may share User Information with our vendors and partners who perform functions on our or our clients’ behalf and require access to such information to provide us with services or do work for us. Examples include: analyzing data, fraud prevention, hosting data, engaging technical support for our technology platform, and performing analysis related to our technology platform and related services.

#### **Information Our Customers and Vendors Collect**

Our clients, our vendors, and our clients’ vendors, who use our technology may use their own tags, pixels, cookies, or other similar technology (or those of their other affiliates) within their advertisements and on certain websites. We are not responsible for our clients’, vendors’ and/or our clients’ vendors’ use of such tracking technologies or for their privacy practices.

### **Your Opt-Out Choices**

There are many ways to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising that our clients may conduct using our technology. Note that different devices use different identifiers and different technologies, so that you must opt out separately from each browser and each device that you would like to be opted out. If you opt-out of targeted advertising, we will no longer collect User Information described above from the opted-out device.

#### Display

Should you wish to opt-out of the use of information about the websites you visit in order to deliver targeted advertising to you, you can do so using the opt-out tool on our website, using the check box below:

Additionally, you can opt-out by using any of the following three mechanisms:

You can opt-out of targeted advertising by NAI participating companies by visiting the NAI’s opt-out page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

You can out of targeted advertising by companies that adhere to the DAA Self-Regulatory Principles by visiting the DAA’s opt-out page at http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

Please note that these opt-outs operate by placing a cookie on your device that is unique to the browser and device you use to opt-out. They may not function properly if you have configured your browser to reject certain cookies. If you change browsers or your device, or delete the cookies on your device, you will need to opt-out again. You also can set your browser to notify you when a cookie is being set and to block most cookies, including ours.

#### Mobile

Your device may give you the ability to opt-out of the use of information about the apps you use in order to serve you ads that are targeted to your interests (see “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads” or “Opt out of Ads Personalization” under your settings menu on Android devices or “Limit Ad Tracking” under your settings menu on iOS devices).

You may stop the collection of location information by particular apps or from your device as a whole at any time by changing the preferences on your mobile device. For more information on how to change your preferences, please see http://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice.

#### Television & Internet Connected Devices

Your Internet connected device (e.g. a smart TV or a set-top box) may give you the ability to opt-out of the use of information for advertising purposes. To determine if your Internet connected device has these options, please visit your device’s settings menu. For more information on how to change your preferences, please see https://www.networkadvertising.org/internet-connected-tv-choices/.

### **Your Choices and Rights**

If you live in certain jurisdictions such as the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the United Kingdom (“UK”), Switzerland, or California, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the collection, processing, and use of information about you.

In particular, you have the right to: (i) request access and obtain a copy of your User Information, and (ii) request erasure, or deletion of your User Information. You may also have the right to request rectification of your User Information, to obtain your User Information in a portable format, to object to or restrict the processing of your User Information, to prevent the use of your User Information for particular purposes, and to not be discriminated against for exercising your rights.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please see our Data Opt Out Policy for instructions on how to do so.

### **Information Retention**

The cookies set out on your device by our advertising technology expire no later than 366 days after the last time you visited a Digital Media Property using our advertising technology.

We typically store the User Information we collect from your device, such as IP address and other information described above, in our systems for up to 90 days before we anonymize and aggregate that data into summary reports.

In some cases, we may keep some of the User Information for longer periods of time where required under certain laws or to comply with law enforcement or regulatory requests – for example, those relating to corporate governance, taxation, money laundering and financial reporting legislation.

### Security

We use industry-standard technical and organizational security measures to help protect information transmitted over or stored on our systems. Please note that no transmission or storage of information, however, can ever be guaranteed to be completely secure, though we take all reasonable precautions to protect against security incidents.

**Additional Information for California Residents**
---------------------------------------------------

If you are a resident of California, please review these additional privacy disclosures.

### Your Rights

California law requires us to disclose the categories of personal information we collect and how we use them, the categories of sources from which we collect personal information, and the third parties with whom we share personal information, which we have explained above. We are also required to communicate information about rights you have under California law—for information about these rights, please see “Your Choices and Rights” above. You also have the right to request what information we collect and how we use and disclose it. You may exercise these rights by visiting our Data Subject Rights policy. Please note that because most of the information we store can only identify a particular browser or device, and cannot identify you individually, you need to provide us with some additional information to enable us to identify the User Information we hold about you, if any, and ensure that we accurately fulfill your request. If you have any questions about your rights or our disclosures, you may reach us at [\[email protected\]](https://advangelists.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

In addition, we are required to provide you certain information about the business and commercial purposes for which we collect and share your personal information. We use and disclose the information we collect for the business purposes described in the “How We Use User Information” section of this policy, including: to allow our clients to select and display advertisements, to understand how users interact with our services, for auditing purposes, to detect security incidents, to prevent fraud, debug, and repair errors, and for other purposes described above.

### Do Not Sell My Personal Information

Advangelists does not sell User Information, but our clients may use our technology to buy or sell personal information as defined by California law. If you wish to opt out of the use of your personal information for interest-based advertising purposes, you may do so by clicking here or by following the instructions under Your Opt-Out Choices above. Note that because these opt outs are specific to the device or browser on which they are exercised, you will need to opt out on each browser and device.

### **Changes to this Policy**

We may update this policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you of any material changes by posting the revised policy on this website, and where necessary, by any other means required by applicable law.

**Contact Us**

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact Advangelists’s Privacy Team by e-mail at [\[email protected\]](https://advangelists.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by post using the details provided below:

Advangelists

Attn: Privacy Team

35 Torrington Lane

Shoreham, NY 11786

You can also contact Advangelists’s Data Protection Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://advangelists.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

©2020 Advangelists LLC, A Mobiquity Technologies Company

×

###### Login to your account

###### contact info

###### Locations

* **New York:** 61 Broadway, Suite 1105, New York, NY 10005 USA
* **Additional Offices:**
* Silicon Valley
* Seattle, WA
* Toronto, Canada

###### Advangelists is a Mobiquity Technologies Company

* 

###### [Privacy policy | GDPR](https://advangelists.com/privacy-policy/)

###### [Consumer Opt-Out](https://advangelists.com/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/)
